Monika Patel

I'm a self-motivated Full Stack Developer who loves to learn and create. I have 3+ years of experience and feel that I would be a great asset to any development or design team. I strive to deliver quality work through focused research and endeavor to be at the edge of emerging technology.

Professional Experience

Feb 2015 - Present

Solution Dynamics – DOT Net Developer

Working within an Agile development environment as a .Net Developer for the web and windows applications development and maintenance. Role established UI and component guidelines to ensure the clear direction & alignment of a consistent UI for the end users. Worked closely with other dev-team leaders and sales to bring a consistent vision for the applications.

- **01.** Produce and maintain data digitalizing fully automated software mainly for the scanning bureau.
- **02.** Manage UI guidelines within the Application Development team.
- **03.** Design eye-catching and fully functional visual reports from the huge database.
- **04.** Responsible for designing and testing HTML Email templates for all the SDL clients.

Aug - Oct 2014

ACE cars rental — Front End Developer

I was part of a small development team, responsible for all front-facing aspects.

INTERMEDIATE

- Photoshop CS6
- HTML5
- -CSS3
- CSS grid Flexbox & Bootstrap 3.X+
- JavaScript, jQuery
- React JS & Redux
- C#
- Regular Expression
- SQL, MySQL & NoSQL
- JIRA Agile Methodology
- GIT command & Source Tree

BASIC

- Adobe Illustrator
- Flutter

- **01.** Re-designed rental cars' portal website for both Australia and New Zealand from scratch.
- **02.** Became more focused on the online booking form across different devices and how to enrich small screen web experiences.
- 03. Managed google analytics, tag manager and ads for the New Zealand portal.
- **04.** Design an attractive email signature for the company's email.

Jan 2013 - Mar 2014

Tatvasoft Ltd — WebDeveloper

Started as Intern and eventually became a responsible part of the small development team, focusing mainly on front-end aspects.

- **01.** Worked with senior developers, designers and insurance service provider to understand a brief of insurance terms.
- **02.** Delivered insurance website for the www.insurox.com

Education

Aug 2009 - Feb 2013

Charotar University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Computer science with GPA 8.42/10

- WordPress
- SASS & LESS
- ES6

Others

- Language:
 Fluent English speaker with Hindi language proficiency.
- Self-Learning:
 Take Udemy courses, read
 Medium articles and attend
 Meetups.

Contact Info

- monikapatel.it@outlook.com
- in/monikapatelit
- +64 221 37 9800
- <u>www.monikapatel.info</u>

Please check out the HTML online version on GitHub

Last updated on Tuesday, October 23, 2018, Portfolio on monikapatel.info